Finding Aid for Michigan Masonic Publications, [185-]-[198-]
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Masonic Publications [185-]-[198-], 1950-1970
Michigan Masonic Publications
7 linear feet
93854 Bd 2
Programs, flyers, handbooks, newsletters, bylaws, directories, rituals, and miscellaneous publications of a variety of Masonic organizations in Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection includes materials donated by Roscoe O. Bonisteel (donor 2035 ), James R. Breakey (donor 4898 ), Charles Fey (donor 3275 ), William C. Hollands (donor 2021 ), Alice Fairman Johnson (donor 7821 ), James Fairbairn Smith (donor 5401 ), and David Williams (donor 3982 ).
The collection is open for research.
The Michigan Masonic Publications collection includes programs, flyers, handbooks, newsletters, bylaws, directories, rituals, and miscellaneous publications of a variety of Masonic organizations in Michigan. Statewide bodies and local bodies in Southeastern Michigan are most strongly represented. Although materials printed as early as the 1850s are found in the collection, the bulk of items date from the 1950s through 1970s.
Histories of organizations and proceedings of the major orders in Michigan, as well as a few reference works relating to freemasonry in general, are cataloged separately in the Michigan Historical Collections printed works catalog.
Subjects:
Freemasonry--Michigan.; Freemasons--Michigan.; Scottish Rite (Masonic order)--Michigan.; Royal Arch Masons--Michigan.; Royal and Select Masters (Masonic order)--Michigan.; Knights Templar (Masonic order)--Michigan.; Order of the Amaranth--Michigan.; Order of the Eastern Star--Michigan.; Michigan Masonic Home.; Ancient Arabic Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine for North America--Michigan.; Mystic Order of Veiled Prophets of the Enchanted Realm--Michigan.; White Shrine of Jerusalem--Michigan.
- Freemasonry in general
  - American Tyler-Keystone (Box 1)
    (scattered issues)
  - German-American lodges (Box 1)
  - Masonic Bible (Box 1)
  - Masonic News (Box 1)
    (special issues)
- Blue Lodge
  (Free and Accepted Masons)
  - Grand Lodge
    - Advance reports 1930-1986, 3 folders (Box 1)
      (scattered dates)
    - Annual communications (Box 1)
    - Directories (Box 1)
    - Michigan Masonic Monitor (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Local lodges
    - Alma (Box 1)
    - Alpena (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor
      - Ann Arbor Masonic News 1945-1980, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous 1890s-1980s, 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Birmingham (Box 2)
    - Brighton (Box 2)
    - Chelsea (Box 2)
    - Detroit (Box 2)
    - Flint (Box 2)
    - Grand Rapids (Box 2)
    - Jackson
      - Jackson Masonic News 1922-1940, 10 folders (Box 2)
      - Jackson County Masonic News 1940-1950, 3 folders (Box 2)
      - Jackson Masonic News 1950-1974 and Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Lansing (Box 2)
    - Monroe (Box 2)
    - Muskegon (Box 2)
    - Pinckney (Box 2)
    - Pontiac (Box 2)
    - Royal Oak (Box 2)
    - Saginaw (Box 3)
    - Ypsilanti (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
- Scottish Rite
  - Michigan Council of Deliberation and Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Local bodies
    - Valley of Bay City (Box 3)
    - Valley of Detroit
      - Bylaws (Box 3)
      - Reunion programs 1926-1976, 3 folders (Box 3)
      - Scottish Rite Bulletin (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Valley of Grand Rapids
      - Scottish Rite News (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Valley of Marquette (Box 3)
- York Rite
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Chapter
    (Royal Arch Masons)
    - Grand Chapter (Box 3)
    - Local chapters
      - Ann Arbor (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Cryptic/Council
    (Royal and Select Masters)
    - Grand Council (Box 3)
    - Local councils (Box 3)
  - Knights Templar
    - Grand Commandery
      - Advance reports (Box 3)
      - Annual conclaves (Box 3)
      - Directories (Box 3)
      - Handbooks, rituals, etc. (Box 3)
      - Programs, etc. (Box 4)
    - Local commanderies
      - Adrian (Box 4)
      - Ann Arbor, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Detroit (Box 4)
      - Hillsdale (Box 4)
      - Howell (Box 4)
      - Lansing (Box 4)
      - Monroe (Box 4)
      - Northville (Box 4)
      - Redford (Box 4)
      - Ypsilanti (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
- Other Masonic bodies
  (including side degrees, adoptive masonry, African American masonry, etc.)
  - Amaranth
    - Grand Court, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Local courts (Box 4)
  - Daughters of Mokanna (Box 4)
  - De Molay (Box 4)
  - Eastern Star
    - Grand Chapter
      - Eastern Star Magazine (Box 4)
      - Handbooks, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Instructions (Box 4)
      - Law, 1 folders (Box 4)
      - Law, 1 volumes (Box 5)
      - Programs (Box 5)
      - Ritual of 1867 (Box 5)
      - Ritual, Miscellaneous (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Local chapters
      - Adrian (Box 5)
      - Ann Arbor, 3 folders (Box 5)
      - Bay City (Box 5)
      - Belleville (Box 5)
      - Chelsea (Box 5)
      - Dexter (Box 5)
      - Farmington (Box 5)
      - Flint (Box 5)
      - Garden City (Box 5)
      - Hillsdale (Box 5)
      - Howell (Box 5)
      - Lansing (Box 5)
      - Manchester (Box 5)
      - Milan (Box 5)
      - Monroe (Box 6)
      - Nankin (Box 6)
      - Onondaga (Box 6)
      - Owosso (Box 6)
      - Pinckney (Box 6)
      - Saginaw (Box 6)
      - Saline (Box 6)
      - Tecumseh (Box 6)
      - Walled Lake (Box 6)
      - Ypsilanti (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Washtenaw County Association (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous associations (Box 6)
  - High twelve clubs (Box 6)
  - Jesters (Box 6)
  - Masonic mutual benefit associations (Box 6)
  - Michigan Masonic Home, 3 volumes; 1 folders (Box 6)
  - Mystic Shrine
    - The Moslemite 1945-1979, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Prince Hall Grand Lodge (Box 7)
  - Rainbow (Box 7)
  - Veiled Prophets
    - Michigan (Box 7)
    - Local grottos
      - Ann Arbor (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - White Shrine
    - Michigan (Box 7)
    - Local shrines
      - Ann Arbor (Box 7)
      - Battle Creek (Box 7)
      - Davis (Box 7)
      - Dearborn (Box 7)
      - Detroit (Box 7)
      - Farmington (Box 7)
      - Flint (Box 7)
      - Highland Park (Box 7)
      - Howell (Box 7)
      - Lincoln Park (Box 7)
      - Plymouth (Box 7)
      - Pontiac (Box 7)
      - Royal Oak (Box 7)
      - Saginaw (Box 7)
      - Warren (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - York Cross of Honor (Box 7)